Guide to the Malcolm Goldstein Papers MSS.350
Fales Library and Special Collections
Malcolm Goldstein Papers
1955-2019
1970-2000
Fales Library and Special Collections
Goldstein, Malcolm, 1936-
MSS.350
52.25 Linear Feet in 52 boxes
Malcolm Goldstein is a composer and violinist primarily concerned with structured improvisation and a unique style which he calls "soundings." He writes graphic scores which combine elements of standard musical notation, calligraphy, written instructions, and collage. Goldstein has collaborated with many dancers, writers, and musicians, most frequently with Philip Corner and Allison Knowles. The Malcolm Goldstein Papers contais scores, documentation of performances, writings, publicity, and administrative documents relating to Goldstein's work as composer, musician, collaborator, writer, curator, and professor.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open to researchers.
Provenance
The Malcolm Goldstein Papers were donated to the Fales Library & Special Collections by Goldstein in 2012. Accretions were donated by Goldstein in 2013-2015, 2018, and 2019. Accession numbers associated with these donations are 2012.350, 2013.350, 2014.350, 2015.350, 2018.090, and 2019.044.
Appraisal
In August 2018 a curatorial decision was made to not accept into the 2018 accretion: a computer floppy disk with existing duplicate analog material and two audiocassette recordings of a non-Goldstein concert.
Arrangement
The material has been arranged into nine series and some separated further into subseries:
Series I: Music Projects
Series II: Writing
Series III: Publicity
Series IV: Administrative
Series V: Commercially Released Media
Series VI: Non-commercially Released Audio
Series VII: Non-commercially Released Video
Series VIII: Data Storage
Series IX: Malcolm Goldstein's Notes on the Collection
Biographical Note
Malcolm Goldstein is a composer and violinist primarily concerned with structured improvisation and a unique style which he calls "soundings." He writes graphic scores which combine elements of standard musical notation, calligraphy, written instructions, and collage. Goldstein has collaborated with many dancers, writers, and musicians, most frequently with Philip Corner and Allison Knowles.
Born on March 27, 1936 in Brooklyn NY, Malcolm Goldstein attended Columbia University from 1952 through 1959 where he studied with Otto Leuning and Antonio Miranda. In 1962 he began performing with the Judson Dance Theater, shortly followed by participation in the NY Festival of the Avant Garde and the Experimental Intermedia Foundation. In 1963 he co-founded the Tone Roads chamber ensemble with Philip Corner and James Tenney. Tone Roads, which takes its name from a mid-career composition by Charles Ives, showcased works by Ives, Ruggles, Cage, and Varese. Goldstein went on to work on a critical edition of Ives' work. He also wrote extensively about these musicians as well as about improvisation. He is the author of the book Sounding the Full Circle distributed by Frog Peak Music. He has traveled extensively, performing in countries around the world, and has received many awards including the Prix Acustica International by WDR.
Goldstein has held teaching positions at Columbia-Princeton Electronic Music Center (1959-1960), Columbia College (1961-1965), the New School for Social Research (1963-1965, 1967-1969), the New England Conservatory (1965-1967), Dickinson College (1969-1971), Goddard College (1972-1974), and Bowdoin College (1978-1982). Goldstein has curated and performed in many concerts at these institutions as well as in festivals around the world.
Sources:
The Living Composers Project.
Grove Music Online.
Audiovisual Access Policies and Procedures
Access copies for some audiovisual materials in the collection are available by appointment for reading room viewing and listening only.
Related Materials
Judson Memorial Church Archive (MSS 094)
Scope and Content
The Malcolm Goldstein Papers include scores, documentation of performances, writing, correspondence, publicity, administrative records, audio, video, and data storage. The materials document Goldstein's role as a composer, musician, curator, writer and educator. The collection is arranged into nine series:
Series I: Music Projects comprises scores and documentation of performances. In addition to scores created by Goldstein there are several pieces made by other composers. Notebooks contain drafts of various works in progress.
Series II: Writing comprises unpublished article drafts, interviews, published works, and correspondence. Correspondence is mostly from others with Malcolm Goldstein as the recipient with a few exceptions.
Series III: Publicity is comprised of reviews, photographs, and ephemera documenting performances and commercial releases.
Series IV: Administrative comprises administrative materials reflecting Goldstein's organization of concerts, contracts, grants, music production, and teaching materials.
Series V: Commercially Released Media comprises audio, video, and vinyl sound discs in which Malcolm Goldstein is either the main musician or is featured as a collaborator on the recording.
Series VI: Non-commercially Released Audio comprises audiocassetes and sound discs documenting performances and interviews.
Series VII: Non-commercially Released Video comprises VHS and DVD elements primarily documenting performances.
Series VIII: Data Storage comprises floppy discs and CD-Rs storing visual documentation of performances.
Series IX: Malcolm Goldstein's Notes on the Collection comprises Goldstein's lists and inventories of the collection as it was delivered to the Fales Library and Special Collections.
A 2018 accretion contains Goldstein's writings on the music of Charles E. Irving, specifically a 2016 booklet Charles Ives -- String Quartet No. 2 -- Critical Edition which includes the booklet, as well as supporting work files with edited drafts, letters, notated scores, 1946 sound recordings of the piece, and reviewer notes. Concert programs and reviews of his performances from 2014 to 2016 and Goldstein interview transcripts and articles from 2016-2017 is also in this accretion. Material on Goldstein projects include 1992 Die Moltkerei Gallery original material and descriptions of his Moroccan Project from 2009. Updated copies of existing pieces in the collection as well as more recent works and performance notes for Wandering Still, This Full Breath/Gesture Sounding, and If Not Now, When? can also be found in this collection, dating from 2017 to 2018.
Music -- Manuscripts.; Improvisation in dance; Improvisation (music); Composers -- United States -- 20th century; Gamelan.; Audiocassettes.; Modern dance -- New York (State) -- New York; Avant-garde (Music); Sheet music.; scores (documents for music); Goldstein, Malcolm, 1936-; Cage, John; Celli, Joseph; Corner, Philip; Higgins, Dick, 1938-1998; Ives, Charles, 1874-1954; Judson Dance Theater; Kaul, Matthias; Knowles, Alison, 1933-; Oliveros, Pauline, 1932-; Ruggles, Carl, 1876-1971; Tenney, James; Varese, Edgard, 1883-1965
- Series I: Music Projects, 263529
  Scope and Content
  The Series comprises scores and documentation of performances. It is separated into three subseries: Projects A-Z, Other Musicians, and Notebooks and Sketches. Each subseries is described more fully below.
  - Subseries A: Projects A-Z, 263530
    Subseries A: Projects A-Z contains scores, source material, and documentation of performances for music projects. Each project was labeled by Malcolm Goldstein and titles were transcribed from his notes.
    Arrangement
    Projects are listed alphabetically as they were upon arrival.
    - "Absolute Cow", 1988; 263536 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - "As it were"- [score], 1996; 263537 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - "As it were"- [score], 1996; 263538 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - "As it were, another"- [score and instructions with permission from Jasper Johns], April 22, 1998; 263539 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - "August Light"- Dia Art Foundation [Photographs], May, 1988; 263540 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - "Ayre(s) full the bellows delight" [score], 2010; 263542 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - "Bataille"- [photographs], September, 2002; 263543 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - "Because a circle is not enough" with "An attempt to define what it is to be 'in the sound" [See also writing series], 1990; 2000; 263544 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - "Between hair and wood/changes"- [score], September 16, 1980; 263545 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - "Between two spaces"- [score, sketches, text] [1 of 4], 1993-1994; 263546 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - "Between two spaces"- [score, sketches, text] [see also: oversize materials] [2 of 4], 1993-1994; 263547 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - "Between two spaces"- [PrixAcustica International Award] [3 of 4], 1993-1994; 263548 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - "Between two spaces"- score/structure for horspiel [4 of 4], 1993; 263549 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - "Between two spaces"-Doors project [photographs] [1 of 3], 1993; 263550 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - "Between two spaces"-Doors project [photographs] [2 of 3], 1993; 263551 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - "Between two spaces"-Doors project [sketches] [3 of 3], 1993; 263552 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - "Boundless the Source, Overflowing in Song", 2019 (Box 53, Folder 1)
    - "A breaking of vessels, becoming song" for Barbara Held- [score], January 2, 1981; 263553 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - "Breath River Route"- [photographs] [1 of 3], 1986; 263554 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - "Breath River Route"- [slides and negatives] [2 of 3], 1986; 263555 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - "Breath River Route"- [photographs] [3 of 3], 1986; 263556 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - "Breath within cycles becoming"-[score], 1983; 263557 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - "Bridging the Gap"- [score], 1987; 263558 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - "Broken Canons" for Charles Ives - [score], 2011; 263559 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - "A brutal bit of these times" Bratislava Erik Satie project- [score], 1995; 263560 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - "The Burrow"/ "Kafka in These Times"- see also "Dwelling on Dwelling", 1992; 263561 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - "By way of definition" a sounding for Jackson Mac Low - [score], 1996; 263562 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - "Can it be done in public? Tango" with "Toccata, ma non suonare" - [score], 1976-1984; 263563 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - "Cantos II" - [score], 1976-1977; 263564 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - "Casa del popola" - [photographs], 2007-2008; 263565
    - "Cascades of the Brook: Bachwasserfall"- Original Artwork, 1984 (Folder 10)
    - "Cascades of the Brook: Bachwasserfall"- [Instructions and philosophy], January 15, 1985; 263566 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - "Cascades of the Brook: Bachwasserfall"- Violin I [collaged score], 1985; 263567 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - "Cascades of the Brook: Bachwasserfall"- Violin II [collaged score], 1985; 263568 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - "Cascades of the Brook: Bachwasserfall"- Viola [collaged score], 1985; 263569 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - "Cascades of the Brook: Bachwasserfall"- Cello/Bass [collaged score], 1985; 263570 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - "Cascades of the Brook: Bachwasserfall"- Flute [collaged score], 1985; 263571 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - "Cascades of the Brook: Bachwasserfall"- Oboe [collaged score], 1985; 263572 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - "Cascades of the Brook: Bachwasserfall"- Clarinet [collaged score], 1985; 263573 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - "Cascades of the Brook: Bachwasserfall"- Alto Saxophone [collaged score], 1985; 263575 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - "Cascades of the Brook: Bachwasserfall"- Bassoon [collaged score], 1985; 263576 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - "Cascades of the Brook: Bachwasserfall"- Harpsichord [collaged score], 1985; 263586 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - "Cascades of the Brook: Bachwasserfall"- conductor's score in reduced size and seating arrangment, 1985; 263587 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - "Cascades of the Brook: Bachwasserfall"- first set of xerox copies of orchestral parts, 1985; 263588 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - "Cascades of the Brook: Bachwasserfall"-Brooklyn Philharmonic Concert orchestral parts: Violin I (C. Hafer), 1985; 263589 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - "Cascades of the Brook: Bachwasserfall"-Brooklyn Philharmonic Concert orchestral parts: Violin I (Jill Levy), 1985; 263590 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - "Cascades of the Brook: Bachwasserfall"-Brooklyn Philharmonic Concert orchestral parts: Violin I (Ik Hwan), 1985; 263591 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - "Cascades of the Brook: Bachwasserfall"-Brooklyn Philharmonic Concert orchestral parts: Violin I (Bushman), 1985; 263592 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - "Cascades of the Brook: Bachwasserfall"-Brooklyn Philharmonic Concert orchestral parts: Violin II, 1985; 263593 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - "Cascades of the Brook: Bachwasserfall"-Brooklyn Philharmonic Concert orchestral parts: Violin II (Paul Woodiel), 1985; 263594 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - "Cascades of the Brook: Bachwasserfall"-Brooklyn Philharmonic Concert orchestral parts: Violin II (Carol Havelka), 1985; 263595 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - "Cascades of the Brook: Bachwasserfall"-Brooklyn Philharmonic Concert orchestral parts: Violin II (Marion Guest), 1985; 263596 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - "Cascades of the Brook: Bachwasserfall"-Brooklyn Philharmonic Concert orchestral parts: Viola, 1985; 263597 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - "Cascades of the Brook: Bachwasserfall"-Brooklyn Philharmonic Concert orchestral parts: Viola, 1985; 263604 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - "Cascades of the Brook: Bachwasserfall"-Brooklyn Philharmonic Concert orchestral parts: Viola (Ron Carbone), 1985; 263605 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - "Cascades of the Brook: Bachwasserfall"-Brooklyn Philharmonic Concert orchestral parts: Viola (Janet Hill), 1985; 263606 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - "Cascades of the Brook: Bachwasserfall"-Brooklyn Philharmonic Concert orchestral parts: Cello/Bass (Rosenfeld), 1985; 263607 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - "Cascades of the Brook: Bachwasserfall"-Brooklyn Philharmonic Concert orchestral parts: Cello (Fitzgerald), 1985; 263608 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - "Cascades of the Brook: Bachwasserfall"-Brooklyn Philharmonic Concert orchestral parts: Cello (M.N.), 1985; 263609 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - "Cascades of the Brook: Bachwasserfall"-Brooklyn Philharmonic Concert orchestral parts: Cello/Bass, 1985; 263610 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - "Cascades of the Brook: Bachwasserfall"-Brooklyn Philharmonic Concert orchestral parts: Cello/Bass (Bruno), 1985; 263611 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - "Cascades of the Brook: Bachwasserfall"-Brooklyn Philharmonic Concert orchestral parts: Cello/Bass, 1985; 263612 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - "Cascades of the Brook: Bachwasserfall"-Brooklyn Philharmonic Concert orchestral parts: Flute (R.D.), 1985; 263613 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - "Cascades of the Brook: Bachwasserfall"-Brooklyn Philharmonic Concert orchestral parts: Oboe, 1985; 263614 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - "Cascades of the Brook: Bachwasserfall"-Brooklyn Philharmonic Concert orchestral parts: Clarinet, 1985; 263615 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - "Cascades of the Brook: Bachwasserfall"-Brooklyn Philharmonic Concert orchestral parts: Alto Saxophone, 1985; 263616 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - "Cascades of the Brook: Bachwasserfall"-Brooklyn Philharmonic Concert orchestral parts: Harpsichord, 1985; 263617 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - "Cascades of the Brook: Bachwasserfall"-Brooklyn Philharmonic Concert orchestral parts: Bassoon (Morelli), 1985; 263618 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - "Cento Anni di Suoni"- Five graphic realizations (reduced size), March 27, 1998; 263619 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - "Cento Anni di Suoni", 1997-1999; 263620 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - "Cento Anni di Suoni"- [Photographs], 1998; 263755 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - "Cento Anni di Suoni"- 100th Birthday Celebration for Malcolm Goldstein's Violin [photographs], 1998; 263758 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - "A Chippewa Love Story" -[score], December 19, 1978; 263761 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - "Circular Breath-Space" from "Wheelock Mountain"- [score], 1972; 263762 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - "Concerning melody" - [score], 1998; 263763 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - "Configurations in darkness" - [score], 1995; 263764 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - "Configurations in darkness" - Tun Art Concert [photographs], November, 1996; 263766 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - "Contemplation (View)" - [score], 1982; 263767 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - "A Convergence of Distances" - [score], 1994-1995; 263772 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - "Counting Cow Bells" - Gamelon ensemble with "Fiddling Cow Bells" magnetic tape collage [score], 1991; 263773 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - "Crossing the Equator" - [score], 1996-1999; 263774 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - "A Cultivation of Field" -[score], 2005; 263775 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - "Cycladic Imprints" with Carolee Schneeman [with photographs], 1988; 263779 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - "Dancers Moving Sound" - [score], November 16, 1984; 263780 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - "Darkness Becoming Narrative" - [score], 2009; 263781 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - "Death: Act or fact of dying" partial reflections on Vietnam [score], November, 1967; 263782 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - "Death: Act or fact of dying" partial reflections on Vietnam [score], November, 1967; 263783 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - "Death: Act or fact of dying" partial reflections on Vietnam- German translation "Tod: Akt oder Tat des Sterbens" [score], 1982; 263784 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - "Death: Act or fact of dying" Vienna - Photographs by Manfred Winter, May, 1982; 263785 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - "Divisions of Ground" - [score], 1998; 263786 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - "Doppelperformance" with Dorethea Rust [inkjet prints], 2008; 263787 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - "Dwelling on dwelling" [with Bart Uchida at The Sharon Arts Center], March 6- April 7, 1994; 263788 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - "The Edges of Sound Within" - [score and sketches], 1985; 263789 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - "The Edges of Sound Within" - [photographs], November, 1987; 263808 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - "Elegia" Poem by Villatoro - [score], 1987; 263809 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - "Emanations" -[score], November, 1962; 263810 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - "An Enactment of Absence" - [score], 1995; 263811 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - "Espaces en movement" -[score], 2010; 263812 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - "Evening Music/ October" -[score], 1988; 263813 (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - "Fiddling Cow Bells" -[score], 1988; 263814 (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - "Fire in the Valley" - photographs by Michael Wilderman, 1997; 263815 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - "For Jackson, A Memorial Celebration (a la Jackson Mac Low)" - [score], March 5, 2005; 263816 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - "Found Harmonies (les harmonies trouvees)" in memoriam Jim Tenney - [score], 2011; 263817 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - "The Fragility of Line/ Points Extending" -[score], September 29, 1982; 263818 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - "Fragments of the Wall" [1 of 2], [2004-2005]; 263819 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - "Fragments of the Wall" [2 of 2], [2004-2005]; 263820 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - "Fragments of the Wall"- Photographs by Rehab Nazzal, [undated]; 263821 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - "Fragments of the Wall" Revised Version -[score with source material], 2008; 263822 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - "Fragments of the Wall"- texts "graffiti" [with French translation], July 31, 2006; [undated]; 263823 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - "Fragments of the Wall"- Dossier on Palestine vol.7, no.43, October 28, 2002; 263824 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - "Fragments of the Wall"- Palestinian Graffiti photographs by Monika Borgmann [inkjet prints], [1991]; 263825 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - "Fragments of the Wall"- Program texts English and French, [undated]; 263826 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - "Fragments of the Wall"- Music/Theater [score], 2007-2008; 263827 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - "Fragments of the Wall"- Music/Theater final revised version [score], 2008; 263828 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - "Free at Last, Free at Last"- [program notes and press releases], November, 1985; 263829 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - "Free at Last, Free at Last", 1986; 263830 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - "Free at Last, Free at Last", 1986; 263831 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - "Free at Last, Free at Last", 1986; 263832 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - "Free at Last, Free at Last"- [photographs], 1986; 263834 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - "Frog Pond at Dusk" - [score], 1970; 263835 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - "Games for Musicians with Dancers Obbligato" for Elaine Summers [score], 1983; 263836 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - "Gentle Rain Preceeding Mushrooms" (in memoriam for John Cage) [score], 1992; 263837 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - "Hardscrabble Songs" [score], 2000; 263838 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - "Hues of the Golden Ascending" [score], April, 1979; 263839 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - "Hues of the Spectrum" for Daichi Saito's film "Trees of Syntax, leaves of Axis" [score], 2008; 263840 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - "If Not Now, When?", 2018 (Box 51, Folder 9)
    - "If Thoreau Had Played the Violin" [score, notes], 2014; 276320 (Box 49, Folder 3)
    - "Illuminations from Fantastic Gardens" for Elaine Summers, "Fantastic Gardens: An Evening of Dance, Judson Dance Theater" [score], 1964; 263841 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - "Illuminations from Fantastic Gardens" for Elaine Summers, "Fantastic Gardens: An Evening of Dance, Judson Dance Theater" [score], 1964; 263847 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - "Illuminations from Fantastic Gardens"- Reduced Size Photocopies [score], 1964; 263854 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - "In and Out of Silence" - Violin part of performance in Munich with Barbara Hammann and Alison Knowles, August 18, 2004; 263855 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - "In and Out of Silence" - Performance in Munich with Barbara Hammann and Alison Knowles, September 25-28, 2004; 263856 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - "In and Out of Silence" - Performance in Munich with Barbara Hammann and Alison Knowles [photographs by Vollier Derlath], September, 2004; 263857 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - "In Search of Tone Roads #2" for Charles Ives [score], 2013; 263858 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - "In the beginning...so also, the end" with "Captain Hume's Lamentations" [score], 1997; 263859 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - "Instant Chance" for dance of Elaine Summers [score], March 19, 1965; 263860 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - "Interludes" [score], November 7, 2000; 263861 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - "Ishi/ 'man waxati' Soundings" [score], 1988; 263863 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - "Ishi/ time changing spaces" [score and photographs], 1988; 264026 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - "Ishi/ time changing spaces" [with photographs], 1988; 264027 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - "It were another" [score], 1998; 264035 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - "Jade Mountain Soundings" [score], 1983; 264036 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - "Jade Mountain Soundings" - montage for "Ear as Eye" show with improv visual poem [score], 1996-1998; 264037 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - "Karlsplatz Resonanz" [score], 1983; 264038 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - "Klangbild /Munchen" [score], 1996; 264039 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - "The Life Cycle of Stones" violin and vocal parts [score], 1987; 264040 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - "The Life Cycle of Stones", 1987; 264041 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - "The Life Cycle of Stones" [photographs and slides], 1987; 264042 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - "The Life Cycle of Stones", 1987; 264043 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - "The Life Cycle of Stones", 1987; 264045 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - "The Life Cycle of Stones" [photographs], 1987; 264046 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - "Ludlow Blues" [score], 1963; 264048 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - "Majority -1964" for Charles Ives [score], 264049 (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - "Majority -1964" for Charles Ives [score], 264050 (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - "Majority -1964" for Charles Ives [score], 264051 (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - "A Map of Virginia" -names of tribes, January 21, 2001; 264053 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - "A Map of Virginia", [undated]; 264055 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - "A Map of Virginia", [undated]; 264056 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - "A Map of Virginia", [undated]; 264057 (Box 6, Folder 4)